Jackson: This is the marquee, Claude broke a post-quantum cipher.
Jackson: It's Bitcoin next, Tyler is back on the Bitcoin topics.
Chris: Is it over like, you know, maybe there is a vulnerability here
Chris: that maybe even a human auditor would miss.
Chris: But I can't find it because Fable thinks I'm trying to steal $15 billion, which I'm not.
Jackson: Yeah. I mean, you've totally flipped me now, Tyler.
Jackson: Now I'm like scared that if the models were open that people would kill me.
Jackson: So now I want them to be restricted, I guess.
Jackson: Right. This is what I'm talking about.
Jackson: Give me the CRISPR agent.
Chris: Like I'm built different. I'll work it out. I'll figure it out.
Chris: Just give me that.
Tyler: No, I can totally see a world where you like let an agent shop for you.
Tyler: Say like, go find me.
Jackson: But I'm glad we finally talked about it into payments.
Jackson: It looks like we're going to end this pod up two bucks.
Jackson: That's 2% on the hundo.
Jackson: So I think we're building quite the nest egg for our retirement boys.
Jackson: Yo, what's up, everybody?
Jackson: We got our boys back.
Jackson: It's Jackson, but who else is it?
Tyler: Tyler right here, as always, well, except for last week.
Chris: And also Chris always except for last week.
Jackson: The boys are back.
Jackson: You know, I'm not going to lie last week when I was doing it alone, which was super
Jackson: awkward.
Jackson: I was like, what if they never come back?
Tyler: So with your dedication, Jackson, you just kept the torch alive.
Chris: Yeah, huge, huge shout out to Jackson.
Chris: I don't know if I could carry a podcast by myself.
Chris: I think I can barely carry a third of it.
Chris: So just massive props for keeping it going.
Jackson: This is the perfect time to transition to the death of Bitcoin and the death of security
Jackson: of Bitcoin.
Tyler: Yeah, I'm not a cryptographer.
Tyler: I'm an amateur Bitcoin appreciator.
Tyler: But my understanding of this was that it broke a quantum safe cryptographic system that
Tyler: is not really used anywhere.
Tyler: So there's like a bunch of my understanding is like quantum safe cryptography is a much
Tyler: newer branch, newer field.
Tyler: And a lot of the algorithms and stuff there just has like less time in the field, less
Tyler: battle testing than the stuff that's like tried and true that is quantum vulnerable.
Tyler: Like Bitcoin's cryptography is some parts of it are quantum vulnerable, which means that
Tyler: a quantum computer using Shor's algorithm could, in theory, factor it if it is a big
Tyler: enough quantum computer with enough capacity.
Tyler: Like really far away from that threshold, but some people are worried that that's
Tyler: accelerating.
Tyler: But like one of the things that you would do if you were worried about quantum computers
Tyler: coming soon is migrate Bitcoin's cryptography to a quantum safe cryptography system.
Tyler: And there's like a bunch of ones that are quantum safe that are candidates that you could
Tyler: choose, but they're like newer.
Tyler: They've had like less scrutiny. I think they kind of rely on like the academic
Tyler: cryptography community, like people looking at them and trying to break them.
Tyler: And like I don't know how many people in the world have the capability or expertise to
Tyler: like look at these algorithms and actually scrutinize them.
Tyler: And they probably all work for like the NSA and like don't don't do this out of the
Tyler: goodness of their heart and report it back.
Tyler: So like it's theorized that a lot of these, not a lot of them, but like there could be
Tyler: potential like classical computing vulnerabilities in these quantum safe crypto
Tyler: algorithms.
Tyler: And anthropic, I guess, as part of some of the stuff they're doing to prove how rad mythos
Tyler: is are like having mythos just look at these quantum safe crypto algorithms and see if it
Tyler: can find vulnerabilities.
Tyler: And it found a vulnerability in one of them.
Tyler: And it seems like people are very impressed.
Tyler: Like it was an impressive vulnerability. It found use some like creativity. The model
Tyler: worked for like hours and hours and hours.
Tyler: And it was kind of funny. The I think the anthropic like posted in their blog, like here
Tyler: are the prompts that we use to do this.
Tyler: And it was literally just like bro being like continue. Look for it.
Tyler: Look for a vulnerability. And like I had to prompt it like three times and then it like
Tyler: popped out this thing that would break the cryptography.
Tyler: So it is very scary. I wouldn't say that this makes me super worried because like I'm
Tyler: sure that they had applied this, you know, have mythos look at the cryptography that are
Tyler: underlying all these important systems is like probably the first order thing they did.
Tyler: And that I would assume that it didn't find vulnerabilities in those or if it did, they've
Tyler: like responsibly disclosed them and they're being patched and they're going to be doing
Tyler: that.
Tyler: And hopefully it turns over without issue, but it certainly puts into the realm of
Tyler: possibility that a smarter model or a different model or trying the same model again
Tyler: could find a vulnerability in some of the cryptography that underlies Bitcoin or really
Tyler: on a cryptographic system.
Tyler: But if there's huge vulnerabilities and like core cryptography that runs the internet,
Tyler: like a lot of things have problems. It isn't only Bitcoin that has this problem, although
Tyler: Bitcoin is like a very prominent example of it.
Tyler: So I'll get off of my soapbox. I think I ate up all the air in the room on that one.
Jackson: So you're sort of saying that a lot of these quantum safe cryptography algorithms were
Jackson: like theorized by like, what do they call those people, deep academics basically, and
Jackson: they're not well battle tested.
Jackson: So maybe this is like a way for anthropic deflects their model, but it actually doesn't
Jackson: imply that because methods can crack this cryptography algorithm that is quantum safe
Jackson: that they can crack non quantum safe and potentially other quantum safe algorithms, which
Jackson: is like what you think when you read the article.
Tyler: Yeah, people probably think like quantum safe, that must be the highest level of safety.
Tyler: And if it can beat that, then all the stuff that's kind of like below it is vulnerable.
Tyler: But that isn't the case. It's like quantum safe just means it's safe against Shor's
Tyler: algorithm. But there can be a classical vulnerability in it, whereas like classic elliptic
Tyler: curve cryptography is vulnerable to quantum computers.
Tyler: We know that, but nobody's found a classic vulnerability to it. And my kind of point was
Tyler: that like, I don't know, what are there like 10 people in the world who can find
Tyler: vulnerabilities in these quantum cryptography algorithms that are really good at it?
Tyler: And now we have like mythos is really good at it. And maybe like GPT, whatever is really
Tyler: good at it. And previously, those 10 people's time was like, they couldn't look at every
Tyler: single algorithm that ever existed and spend an exhaustive amount of time on it.
Tyler: Like spin up a new mythos and have it spend like 20 hours thinking about these and it's
Tyler: very cheap to do that. So I think, you know, in theory, this should just make everything
Tyler: better if you have like a good actor that is scrutinizing this with like very intelligent
Tyler: systems and then, you know, responsibly disclosing and that kind of stuff.
Tyler: Like, I think that's a better world than having a bunch of vulnerabilities in the wild,
Tyler: even if people are like not sophisticated enough to find them.
Chris: I mean, this is if the defenders can get past the model guardrails, then yes, we have a
Chris: better world. But if they cannot, then I mean, question mark, and I look, I have
Chris: something to say about that, but I won't.
Tyler: And if there's another segment, I will, but you shouldn't say, I mean, you, you, you've
Tyler: just let me, you know, bother on. So I think we want to hear some Chris takes here.
Chris: Yeah, I like I totally agree with you.
Chris: But I mean, so one thing that I found interesting about the incident that Jackson spoke
Chris: about on the last part, which was the GPT model escaping its container and hacking
Chris: hugging face.
Chris: So hugging face published the postmortem and in it, I saw that they obviously so
Chris: obviously there's an agent in their system wreaking havoc, so they need an agent to
Chris: defend themselves.
Chris: And I think that's how this is going to look for the foreseeable and they tried to get Opus
Chris: 4.8 to basically go through their systems and work out what was going on.
Chris: And they got guardrailed every single time. So they had to use GLM 5.2, which is an open
Chris: source model from I believe it is it Z.A.I. or moonshot. I think Z.A.I.
Chris: First.
Chris: So so I mean, like we were in this uncomfortable position where the defenders, unless
Chris: they have like a really good relationship with the labs or they have like a special
Chris: access program, a kind of defenseless like they're grasping at whatever tools they can
Chris: get to kind of defend themselves against these adversarial threats.
Chris: And I think, you know, that probably only gets worse unless we work out what we're doing
Chris: with the guardrails.
Chris: And I've personally had similar problems, like I write smart contracts and it is
Chris: impossible to get an audit for your smart contract using the frontier models or very,
Chris: very, very difficult.
Chris: And it just puts you in this awkward position of being like, OK, like, you know, maybe
Chris: there is a vulnerability here that maybe even a human auditor would miss. But I can't
Chris: find it because Fable thinks I'm trying to steal 15 billion dollars, which I'm not.
Jackson: Yeah. Are we all like super like libertarian on the guardrails? Do we all feel like there
Jackson: should be no guardrails or is that just me, in my opinion, alone?
Chris: Is that your feeling, Jackson?
Jackson: Yeah, I mean, why should Anthropic and the government have access to a tool that is way
Jackson: more powerful than like any tool I'm allowed to have? That feels unfair.
Tyler: I guess you could say that the tool, I don't know, like you are like it isn't a human
Tyler: right that you have access to like at F-16.
Jackson: Right. Yeah. Or like it's like a citizen. Yeah, I guess that's true.
Chris: What if I can train my F-16 on an existing F-16? Then is that OK?
Chris: Like by having all the F-16.
Chris: I mean, that's the question. Like, what's the morality of that?
Jackson: I accept your metaphor. And I guess it is similar to like the government wielding power
Jackson: over you through like the weapons that it has that you don't have.
Jackson: But it's also scooping up the power of these intelligence models and wielding it against
Jackson: us as well. I don't know.
Jackson: I guess it's just a different form of weapon that now that they have over us.
Tyler: I mean, I think it's a pretty I don't think that there's like a clear answer from my
Tyler: perspective because I'm definitely more aligned on like less restrictions, more freedoms.
Tyler: People should have access openly to the frontier stuff like that's great. But then I
Tyler: think that if you hear some of the anthropic arguments, like there's they're really
Tyler: worried about like bioterrorism.
Tyler: And like my understanding is that if you have like a fable or mythos class model with no
Tyler: restrictions, you could like the model is intelligent enough to like tell you how to
Tyler: create a pathogen at home that could like create a pandemic or something.
Tyler: So all it takes is like one sicko terrible person out in the world with access to this to
Tyler: like cause really, really terrible outcomes for the whole globe.
Tyler: And so like there is a symmetry there between attacking and defending.
Tyler: And yeah, like what's the right move there? Like I think it feels right to like not
Tyler: deliver that capability to like any anyone in the world unrestricted. But then like so
Tyler: that means, okay, I have a line somewhere and maybe my line, you know, bioterrorism is on
Tyler: one side of my line.
Tyler: Where does that line actually sit? Does it sit with like cryptography or cyber or like,
Tyler: you know, do I think those things should be blocked or included?
Tyler: And certainly the classifiers that were on fable originally were like extremely comical
Tyler: and the like, you know, level of false positives that they would have where it would
Tyler: refuse to do like basic stuff like it refused to tell me about my dog's medicine because
Tyler: it was like a biology question.
Tyler: And I'm like, I don't I just want to know like what the right medicine is for when he got
Tyler: poisoned by mushrooms.
Chris: I think one thing I wonder about is like what is like at this point, like what is the
Chris: time until there is an open source fable or mythos level model, right?
Chris: And then like, you know, if you take that concession, like then maybe that changes what
Chris: the best thing you can do is right. Like if we're if we're six, six months away from
Chris: having like a GLM or Kimmy that is, you know, mythos in all that name, like, how does
Tyler: that change?
Tyler: Like the fact that fable won't do like cybersecurity thinking for you, Chris, it's like,
Tyler: okay, maybe they don't want you to have that, but they really don't want the Chinese labs
Tyler: to have that output and then distill from it.
Tyler: And I think part of the 3D chess is that they want to make their models basically either
Tyler: dumb or return kind of like empty, you know, refusals for these tasks. And then they're
Tyler: like, okay, as long as somebody's distilling us, maybe their model will be really good at
Jackson: generalist coding.
Tyler: That's fine. But we're not going to let them distill like the cyber capabilities, the bioterrorism
Tyler: capabilities. And then if there is an open model that is as smart at coding as fable, it's
Tyler: going to have these like potentially big gaps because it didn't get, you know, that and
Tyler: it's training data.
Tyler: And like potentially, you know, there's enough generalization from having a model or an
Tyler: agent that's super, super good at coding that like it just becomes really good at cyber.
Tyler: But like, I think that it is part of their having these classifiers.
Tyler: It's like to prevent you from misusing it, but also to prevent that capability from
Tyler: leaking through distillation reasoning traces into these open models.
Jackson: Yeah, I mean, you've totally flipped me now, Tyler. Now I'm like scared that if the
Jackson: models were open that people would kill me. So now I want them to be restricted, I guess.
Tyler: I mean, you know, like the internet beam, it's like, how do you want to control this
Tyler: technology? Do you want to use terrorism or like child abuse, you know, and like I feel
Tyler: like a little bit like pulling back that lever by being like bioterrorism.
Tyler: So yeah, I feel like that's usually the things that people go to to justify this type of
Tyler: additional control.
Tyler: I don't know. It's a difficult question.
Jackson: So now that Chris says that there's going to be mythos level open source model in six
Jackson: months. Does that mean we're all going to die? Not from the robots, but because of human
Jackson: generated pathogens from a nefarious edgy 14 year old living in Colorado.
Tyler: I hope not. I mean, that's when, yeah, I don't know what the, what the, how you protect
Tyler: against that. If that type of capability is diffused and it only takes like one motivated
Tyler: bad actor, then yeah.
Jackson: Does that mean we all need to like have our own agents developing anti pathogens
Jackson: monitoring what pathogens are being developed and give me the CRISPR agent.
Chris: Like I'm built different. I'll work it out. I'll figure it out. Just give me that.
Jackson: Yeah. Wow. Well yeah. Thanks again for the insight on the guardrails. I was like, these
Jackson: guardrails are stupid. I just hate being told what to do, but I think you're right. There
Jackson: probably needs to be some, some guardrails.
Tyler: Yeah, totally sucks. And I'm not like super pro guardrail. I'm just kind of like steel
Tyler: manning the case a little bit here and why I think it makes sense.
Tyler: Like they don't want their model distilled. So they make it, um, they don't, you know,
Tyler: provide that capability. And then they're obviously worried about it being used for bad
Tyler: actions, but you don't know where I'm down on this, but I'm not like a hundred percent,
Tyler: uh, like free unrestricted model person.
Tyler: I think because of that, but I'm also probably less restrictive than a lot of the
Tyler: policies that you see right now.
Chris: I just want to say to any anthropic or open AI, uh, listeners that, uh, I can be trusted
Chris: with glass wing or GPT six. Um, I really, really need it. So like, you know, shouts out
Chris: to you guys. If you, if you want to hook me up, you know, I'd be, I'd be very happy only
Chris: for auditing purposes.
Jackson: Just to be clear. Open AI, you better give me early access to GPT six because otherwise I'm
Jackson: not taking back all the shit I've talked about 5.6 and open AI general.
Jackson: The thread is out. We're all a critical piece of this three legged stool that we call the
Jackson: podcast. Speaking of stools, Chris, what's going on with the gamer thumb and how is your
Jackson: week away from the pod?
Chris: Uh, yeah, I mean, so my week away from the pod was good. Uh, I was in Australia. Uh, it
Chris: was very cold.
Chris: Uh, but what it did give me is a chance to recover. So like, I didn't do a lot of typing
Chris: whilst I was there. Uh, and, uh, and yeah, I still have game a thumb. So I don't want to
Chris: tell anyone. Yeah.
Tyler: Did you do any gaming when you were there?
Chris: Absolutely not. No gaming. Okay. Full rest for the thumb. Yeah. Full use your phone. Were
Tyler: you like phone typing?
Chris: Yeah, a little bit. I did deliver the phone. That could be it.
Tyler: Were you wearing your brace the whole time?
Chris: No, I didn't wear the brace at all. So like, I obviously have a compliance issue with
Chris: that thing. Um, I, what I did hold. So a lot of my friends have children.
Chris: I did hold a lot of babies and they told me that babies create game a thumb, like, cause
Chris: you're like shaking them around and stuff. Also, I don't know how babies work.
Tyler: You're not supposed to shake a baby. That's like the thing they have on PSAs for, you
Tyler: know, public health. Um, but yeah, you do get like hand and wrist pain from holding
Tyler: babies all the time because, uh, they're heavy and they like wiggle and you kind of
Tyler: awkwardly hold them.
Jackson: Dr. Tyler is back explaining baby thumb.
Tyler: Yeah. Well, when, uh, I, I got wrist surgery to put a screw in my wrist for a broken bone
Tyler: a week before Marco was born, but it was like on her due date.
Tyler: And so I went into the surgery and I told the surgeon, like, if, if I get a text from my
Tyler: wife that she's going to labor, I'm like calling the surgery off. Like, I don't want it
Tyler: to happen while I'm under.
Tyler: Uh, and they put me under and then I woke up and my wife picked me up, but then like I
Tyler: had a wrist brace on, I think for the first two to three months of Margo's life, which
Tyler: made it really difficult to like hold her and like change diapers and all this stuff.
Tyler: Um, so not the most ideal thing. So Chris, if I can do that for two to three months, um,
Tyler: your compliance on the gamer thumb brace, I don't know, man. I don't know. I think you
Tyler: need to do it for the good of your health.
Chris: Listen, man, I'm not here to be called out. All right. I'm here for like acceptance, you
Chris: know, like I accept your non-compliance and inability to fix this very small problem.
Jackson: What about Tyler? I mean, Tyler, you had problems with that risk for like weeks without
Jackson: even knowing what it was, right? And you kept grinding two handed back hands on the
Jackson: tennis board.
Tyler: Yeah. I think I, uh, did I play you Jackson while I had a broken wrist? I think so. Yeah.
Tyler: Okay. So I broke my wrist playing tennis and I thought it was just sprained.
Tyler: And then I kept like, uh, playing tennis for like two weeks after with a broken wrist and
Tyler: it was kept being painful. And then eventually I went to the doctor and got an x-ray and
Tyler: they revealed that.
Tyler: Um, yeah, I guess that, that puts my, you know, I'm, uh, I'm throwing stones at Chris
Tyler: from my glass house over here.
Jackson: Yeah. We're just putting you back, you know?
Chris: Yeah. Thank you for the backup Jackson. I appreciate that. I was feeling cold cloud a
Jackson: little bit, but we're better now.
Jackson: Tyler, how was your vacation? How much, um, toxin do you want to do? Where did you go
Jackson: anywhere say?
Tyler: We went to, uh, New York and the East coast where I grew up. Uh, it was super nice,
Tyler: lovely summer weather there. Did some swimming with the baby, saw some old friends,
Tyler: family.
Tyler: Yeah. It was lovely. A lot of, uh, a lot of work with like childcare because like I got
Tyler: used to daycare a little bit too much that like cushy life. And then now we're back in
Tyler: like 24 seven childcare mode.
Tyler: It's just pretty, uh, pretty comprehensive. And then actually last night, um, there's
Tyler: this thing with babies where you're supposed to like introduce them to allergens to like
Tyler: test if they're allergic to foods.
Tyler: So you give them like little amounts of stuff and then you see what happens. And so we
Tyler: gave my daughter, uh, egg.
Tyler: And two hours later, she threw up like seven times all over both me and my wife. It was
Tyler: just like, I don't understand how she had that much volume in her stomach. And then she
Tyler: got like pretty sick.
Tyler: And we ended up taking her to the, like the children's hospital just out of like an
Tyler: abundance of caution, but it was pretty sad to see. And I spent the whole evening covered
Tyler: in puke.
Tyler: And then we just drove there without like changing or anything. So I just smelled like
Tyler: baby puke for like five hours. Uh, and then they like eventually, you know, gave her some
Tyler: good medicine.
Tyler: And, um, we got home and like cleaned up and went to bed, but yeah, a little bit of a
Tyler: harrowing night, but everyone is okay, but it sucks because you can't eat egg now and
Jackson: eggs are delicious.
Jackson: That's true. Does baby puke smell better than human, like American or pardon me, adult puke?
Tyler: Um, I don't think either are particularly great, but yeah, it does. It does have like
Tyler: that, like stomach acid kind of Biley like smell that normal puke does.
Tyler: Um, but she's, she's all right. And now we just grossed out all of our listeners. So like
Tyler: the, you know, we just, we just dropped off a half of them and the only people remaining
Tyler: are the people that love the puke talk.
Jackson: So, um, cool. Well, maybe we can do a quick Tyler one minute BIP 110. Is it nothing? Why
Jackson: do I hear about it?
Tyler: I feel like I'm woefully unprepared for this because I think it's just so stupid that I've
Tyler: referred, I've refused to pay attention to it.
Tyler: And so yeah, it's just like the discourse I feel like is so just dumb and I'm just tired
Tyler: of it and I just don't want to pay attention and I'm not going to do anything about it.
Tyler: And it will probably blow over in a few months. Um, I can try to give you my like
Tyler: understanding of it from a very high level, which is that there have been people for a
Tyler: while that are like very upset that, uh, they believe that there's spam.
Tyler: Bitcoin is being used for spam, which they define as these essentially like NFT kind of
Tyler: projects like ordinals and inscriptions. And they want to have the ability to block this
Tyler: spam block the use of arbitrary data on the, on the blockchain.
Tyler: And so they are like, okay, people are doing spam and this one specific way right now, we'll
Tyler: block that. And like, we're trying to force a fork for people that will block that. But
Tyler: it's very stupid because it's like, as soon as you block that one way, the people who
Tyler: want that activity to continue are just going to tweak the way it shows up a little bit.
Tyler: Like people have already done this and shown that like there's BIP 110, they have these
Tyler: filters. Um, the people who do ordinals and inscriptions are like, we'll just do it this
Tyler: different way.
Tyler: And now it's BIP 110 compliant and you'll have to fork a second time. And it's like this
Tyler: infinite game of cat and mouse. You just cannot stop people from putting arbitrary data
Tyler: into Bitcoin transactions because, um, you can make arbitrary data really hard to detect.
Tyler: Um, and like you can even, some of the ways that you would force people to do arbitrary
Tyler: data are like much less healthy for Bitcoin. It might bloat the U2XO state. Um, it might
Tyler: mean that nodes have to like validate a bunch of junk data that doesn't actually have any
Tyler: meaning.
Tyler: And so it's being done right now in kind of like a least harm way. And you could
Tyler: potentially force people to do it and more harmful ways, which is bad.
Tyler: So like, I just think it's a very misguided thing. Most people I know, who I respect,
Tyler: think it's extremely misguided and the people who are behind it seem like, um, either misinformed
Tyler: or just like really, um, like they're not arguing in good faith.
Tyler: I don't really know what their motivations are, but it doesn't seem like in good faith to
Tyler: me because it seems so obvious. Uh, and yeah, Bitcoin, I think will, will fork at some
Tyler: point.
Tyler: I think it's like in a couple of weeks. So there's the BIP 110 fork and then there's also
Tyler: this, um, e-cash fork that's going to happen. So we're going to get two potential forks
Tyler: of Bitcoin this year, which hasn't happened for a while.
Tyler: Um, I think both of them will, will die quickly.
Chris: So it's crazy. Bitcoin cash too.
Jackson: Yeah. Yeah. We need another one. Are you, so you're saying that the people that oppose BIP
Jackson: 110, it's not that they, that they disagree that Bitcoin shouldn't have spam.
Jackson: It's that the solution to prevent the spam is really narrow and yeah, I mean, that's
Jackson: basically it. Is that what you're saying, Tyler?
Tyler: Yeah. At the root of it, you can, you, you can really not prevent people from putting
Tyler: arbitrary data into Bitcoin transactions and like the, the solution is like worse than
Tyler: the problem.
Tyler: And it's also like a temporary thing, honestly, like, um, people can afford to do this
Tyler: right now because transaction fees are very low because like nobody is using Bitcoin.
Tyler: Uh, and if that persists and people don't use Bitcoin and don't make Bitcoin transactions
Tyler: on the blockchain because they're holding Bitcoin and ETFs or, um, Bitcoin is not
Tyler: becoming like a money, then, you know, Bitcoin is probably not very successful and it
Tyler: like doesn't really matter.
Tyler: But if Bitcoin is successful, then I expect transaction fees will increase and price out
Tyler: this activity and it will just go away naturally.
Tyler: And so like, I feel like this world that they're trying to solve for where like Bitcoin
Tyler: is successful and relevant, but spam is still economically viable on the main chain.
Tyler: It just is like a stupid, like temporary thing that we shouldn't overreact to, even if we
Tyler: had ways to stop it and we don't have ways to stop it. So it's all so tiring.
Jackson: Kind of a spontaneous topic switch. Um, so like when the fork happens, all of us that
Jackson: have Bitcoin, uh, I guess Bitcoin that's self custody.
Jackson: It's like duplicated, right? One is on the new chain and one is on the old chain.
Jackson: Is it lucrative for people that do forks? Like, do they make any money?
Jackson: Is it possible I can sell my Bitcoin e-cash to, to some Bitcoin e-cash to bag holders
Jackson: that I don't, because I don't want to keep it?
Jackson: Or does the value go to zero so quick that like I can't make money or no one makes any
Jackson: money?
Tyler: Yeah. So it's true. If you, if you hold your own keys and you have like actual Bitcoin UTXOs,
Tyler: like you will have a UTXO on the fork.
Tyler: Um, if you hold your Bitcoin custodially or like in an ETF, then whoever owns the keys
Tyler: backing that Bitcoin will have a corresponding amount of Bitcoin on those chains. But
Tyler: like they may or may not honor that and give you, um, exposure to these forks.
Tyler: Honestly, it's probably not even going to be worth it for them. I, I expect the forks
Tyler: will be not valuable enough to, to warrant like building, you know, uh, ways to handle
Tyler: them.
Tyler: And if you support every little fork of Bitcoin that comes out in that way, then you're
Tyler: like kind of committing infinitely to support all these.
Tyler: I kind of think zip one 10 is just like a publicity stunt. Um, I really don't expect it
Tyler: to be relevant much at all, but it is taking up a lot of like the discourse on, you know,
Tyler: Bitcoin X, which is really sad to see because it's such a stupid discourse.
Tyler: And I think it's like poisoning the vibes and poisoning, like, you know, anyone who comes
Tyler: into Bitcoin at this moment, they're just like, this is the dumbest debate that's ever
Tyler: happened.
Tyler: Like, why would I, why would I want to be part of this community? Um, it's just like sad.
Jackson: I feel like for the, for the dip in the forks. So you're saying that the minor can choose
Jackson: to like go to a different pool.
Jackson: If they don't agree with the minor's decision on which fork to take, is it that easy?
Jackson: Like, is it really easy to switch pools for the minor? Yeah, totally.
Tyler: It's like you just, you have your ASIC and your ASIC has like a configuration.
Tyler: That's like, what is the IP address of your pool to fetch blocks from?
Tyler: And you just change that. I have like a little mini bid X minor in my house. Um, it has
Tyler: like no chance of ever finding a block, but I can go on there right now and update the
Tyler: pool in 30 seconds.
Jackson: But are you mining for yourself or are you mining for a pool?
Jackson: Are you playing the lottery with your bid acts? I am. Yeah. There's, um, it is a pool,
Tyler: but it's like a pool where I get like 99% of the block that I find, I think.
Tyler: So the pool is really just, you're, you're paying them a small amount of a reward that
Tyler: you would find in order to construct the blocks because your minor can't do block
Tyler: construction.
Tyler: It doesn't run a full note. It needs to be told like what block to hash on.
Jackson: Dude, we should just say, screw the perp of fortune. Let's just look at your bid acts for
Jackson: an hour in the pot.
Jackson: It'd be a pretty boring episode.
Chris: We just would read every hash, every single hash.
Chris: We'll see that like, Oh, only three zeros on that one. And we'll just manually look at
Tyler: the skintillating TV.
Tyler: Speaking of fortune, I feel like we, we, we've had one running. Should we introduce it or
Tyler: do we have more fork talk?
Jackson: We can't talk more about it. It's too much.
Chris: Well, speaking of forking things, um, so, uh, I followed your prompts, Tyler, where you
Chris: said that purple fortune should be relative to the podcast.
Chris: Um, uh, we haven't done this segment yet, but, uh, so I, I, so for context,
Chris: I fed GPT 5.6 soul the podcast transcript and I said, Hey, like help us pick a perp like
Chris: that is hopefully going up.
Chris: Uh, that's relevant to the transcript.
Chris: Uh, and it said long native XRP perp at 20 X isolated leverage.
Chris: That is what it chose.
Chris: And, uh, I'll try to summarize some of its reasoning here.
Chris: Uh, it says at the final snapshot XRP was up 1.5% over 24 hours and it had 28.2 million
Chris: daily volume and also X RLP RPL.
Chris: Don't know what that is officially supports X four or two payments using XRP or RL USD.
Chris: And that's it.
Chris: That was its whole reasoning.
Jackson: Uh, God, these GPT models are so bad.
Chris: I mean, he's a great programmer, but as I alluded to on the last podcast, he's like, you
Chris: know,
Chris: it may be like the weird guy at the party sometimes.
Chris: Uh, so let me share this.
Chris: Let me share this.
Tyler: Uh, this really, uh, makes me lose faith.
Chris: Uh, it's, you know, I think it's just a case of like staying in your lane, like, uh, and
Chris: maybe like the lane is not choosing perps for five.
Jackson: Oh, dude.
Jackson: What are you talking about?
Jackson: It's reasoning was shy, but it's, is it we're up.
Chris: Don't we've been under this whole podcast?
Chris: Look at this line.
Chris: There's a recent occurrence.
Chris: We were here before, uh, if we close green, I'm very happy.
Chris: Uh, $2,000 notional. So let's see, we see where we get to.
Tyler: Have you ever been a ripple guy, either of you?
Tyler: Like, I feel like ripple guy is like a very distinct phase that some people go through in
Tyler: the crypto worlds.
Tyler: But I don't, I don't know people who actually are afflicted by that, um, mental illness.
Chris: What do you, what do you think, Tyler?
Chris: Be very careful what you say here.
Tyler: I think, I think Jackson probably has like dabbled in a little bit of ripple.
Tyler: I think Chris, I would say no, no, no hate on you, Jackson.
Tyler: But I feel like you're just like a little bit more exploratory and kind of like, uh, try
Tyler: anything.
Tyler: And then, yeah, maybe Chris and I are like, um, like cynical, like hermits hating on the
Tyler: world from our computer screens.
Jackson: All right. I've been called out. Yes. I have owned ripple.
Jackson: Yes. I've doubled my money under ripple. Nice.
Jackson: And literally an hour before this pod, I was talking to this Argentinian dude, and he
Jackson: said he loves ripple.
Jackson: The rest of it was in Spanish, so I can't tell you why, but the ripple signal is actually
Jackson: high right now.
Jackson: I mean, the purple fortune, the Argentinian dude, and I made some money on it.
Tyler: Yeah. Maybe this is just another invocation of the bell curve meme.
Tyler: And I'm like a sad mid curve person being like, ripple is so dumb.
Tyler: And then, you know, GPT is off there on the right hand side.
Jackson: GPT is the last thing. GPT is the last thing.
Chris: I, uh, yeah, I know I was, I was never a ripple guy.
Chris: And I think like it's due to like a fundamental weakness in my reasoning.
Chris: Like I need something to like be like conceptually beautiful in order for me to believe
Chris: in it.
Chris: And I don't know. I feel like I feel like ripple didn't have that for me.
Chris: I was like, I was like, you know, we're like reinventing Swift, but I mean, that's a
Chris: great story, right?
Chris: And I think that's exactly it. Yeah. I think like I'm maybe I'm poor for this reason.
Tyler: So like, I don't know, like why does Swift need to be reinvented? I don't know.
Chris: I don't know. Why do you need to put two toll boots on a bridge?
Jackson: Like 10 years ago, they're like, there's this new coin and it can be used for
Jackson: international bank transfers.
Jackson: And you're like, what? I love that. I'm in.
Jackson: And that was even before all like the regulatory push that they've been doing, right?
Jackson: Where I think then they got sued. It went down a lot, but then they broke out because
Jackson: they just gave all the ripple to the legislators, right?
Chris: I think I mean, to this point, I think like maybe we're moving into a time where the only
Chris: moat left is regulation.
Chris: And I've like spoken to people around here, San Francisco, that like truly believe that.
Chris: I don't. I don't. But I think a lot of people think like, you know, as you know, if we
Chris: solve engineering, then like the remaining moat for your business is either regulatory or
Chris: regulatory capture.
Tyler: And from like a generalized thesis or one specifically for like Bitcoin and crypto and fintech.
Chris: Yeah, I think I think fintech. But I also think to a lesser extent, a more general thesis,
Chris: like I've spoken to people who are like,
Chris: "Oh, I was going to build an AI wrapper." But then I thought like, you know, regulation
Chris: would be a better moat for my business.
Chris: And so I'm doing something in fintech. I don't know if I agree with that, but it is
Chris: something I've heard, right?
Tyler: Because out of hiring an engineer, I hired like a lobbyist.
Tyler: Yeah, like a team of lawyers.
Chris: Yeah.
Tyler: But I do think some... I bought a lot of world liberty financial and suddenly I could do
Chris: whatever I wanted.
Chris: Exclusive rights to something. Yeah.
Tyler: I do think like the marketing department of Ripple is like amazing.
Tyler: Like every cycle, whatever the trend is, they're like hop on, "Oh, we want red."
Chris: No.
Tyler: Ripple, bros, it's over. But it's like, yeah, like I think the reasoning...
Jackson: Speaking of Ripple and agentic payments, because those two are very related.
Jackson: Sorry, Chris, what were you going to say?
Chris: No, no, yeah. Should we talk about that?
Chris: Should we chat about agentic payments and X402 and MPP and ADP?
Jackson: Yeah, I think maybe we should give the agentic payments a go.
Jackson: I've been baiting our listeners about agentic payments for like a month.
Jackson: So I'll lay the stage.
Jackson: Agentic payments basically means that your chat GPT can like buy stuff for you from like
Jackson: a consumer point of view.
Jackson: And from a business point of view, it could mean that your business could trade with
Jackson: other businesses in an automated way.
Jackson: And you're like just trusting your AI model to do that from a bird's eye point of view.
Jackson: Now, you two, Chris and Tyler, what do you think? Does it have legs? Is it going to
Jackson: happen?
Chris: Okay, I want to layer a little bit of context on top of this.
Chris: There are four agentic payments protocols in the wild.
Chris: So I mean, so I think like the story here is that Coinbase and some affiliated people
Chris: came up with a protocol called X402.
Chris: The idea is that it repurposes the 402 HTTP code, which I think is payment required.
Chris: And it like allows you to do a payment.
Chris: And there are some cool ideas like streaming payments and micro payments dovetailed in
Chris: there.
Chris: But functionally, what it does is you hit this endpoint and then it returns a
Chris: standardized JSON list of the payments that the vendor accepts.
Chris: On top of that spec, there's some stuff like, you know, how to integrate a facilitator to
Chris: facilitate and do the payments for you, which of course is Coinbase by default.
Chris: And was previously based by default, although I think there are more facilitators and
Chris: more chains accepted now.
Chris: So I think that kicked it off.
Chris: From there, I think Google has put their hat in the ring.
Chris: Stripe and Tempo have one called MPP, which is going through the IETF at the moment.
Chris: I think it's in the proposal draft phase.
Chris: And I mean, my take here is they're all much of a muchness, right?
Chris: Like, I think, you know, when anything big like this happens, there's like a war to
Chris: control the standard because maybe you can be on the ground floor and control some of the
Chris: order flow.
Chris: And basically, you know, my criticism of all of these proposals is they're almost
Chris: exclusively exactly this.
Chris: Like, they seem free and open, but like under the hood, you know, there are some minor
Chris: structural advantages to the proposal.
Chris: And I think a great example of this is that Stripe's proposal MPP is a superset of X402.
Chris: So they're like trying to cannibalize the other.
Chris: They're like, okay, well, this has some adoption. Like, why don't we superset this and
Chris: then like layer our own stuff on top and then kind of like try to redirect the flow of
Chris: this river as it's running.
Tyler: They're vampire attacking X402.
Chris: I didn't want to say it, but it seems like that. Yeah.
Jackson: I guess like the protocols for making the payments, you know, these companies are trying
Jackson: to make them and like monopolize that because it's like a way to make a lot of money.
Jackson: But really, we don't even need them, right?
Jackson: You can point Fable with like full computer control at a website and it can navigate the
Jackson: checkout for you. So like beyond the mechanism that the payments go through, do you see
Jackson: yourselves using like letting your agent buy stuff for you?
Chris: I already let my agent do stuff on chain. I would say my agent is the primary way that I
Chris: interact with stuff on chain.
Chris: By the way, look at CDRN/Sigil if you want. You want to know like how to do this. It's
Chris: very cool.
Chris: You mean your GitHub? Yeah, yeah, my GitHub. Look at my GitHub.
Tyler: My agent only buys Ripple. That's the only thing it's allowed to buy.
Jackson: I think you and Chris mix your agents up.
Tyler: No, I can totally see a world where you like let an agent shop for you. Say like go find
Tyler: me these sneakers.
Tyler: Find me the best price.
Tyler: I'm curious, Chris, do you think this is like a winner-take-all thing with these
Tyler: protocols? Because I feel like one thing that agents are really good at is like handling
Tyler: complexity.
Tyler: So if every company has their own flavor of this protocol that's like subtly different,
Tyler: historically, you would think, okay, maybe it's going to coalesce around one.
Tyler: They'll be winner-take-all because of network effects. Nobody wants to support all this.
Tyler: But agents, it's just trivial for them to hop protocol to protocol, know how to interact
Tyler: with it.
Tyler: So I don't know, I could see some of them, multiple of them persisting and it's kind of
Tyler: like a mess, but the AI is so good at disentangling that mess and hopping between
Tyler: different support that it doesn't necessarily converge.
Chris: Yeah, I totally agree. I think like the crispiest form of my take is that none of this
Chris: matters. Like agents will pave over the complexity as they have with programming.
Chris: But we're making this like needlessly worse for humans for just no reason, right? Like
Chris: with standard fragmentation.
Chris: Like if you go to Claude right now and you spin up CDRN/Sigil or any other key management
Chris: MCP that you want and you tell it to do something, it will work it out. It will pull the
Chris: contracts to bridge your funds and execute the payload.
Chris: It doesn't matter if it's Solana or Ethereum. The agents quite adept at figuring out how
Chris: to do things. And I think this will be no different with checkout or traditional payments
Chris: or whatever. Yeah, that's my whole take.
Tyler: Okay, I think that covers like the protocol level, but then there's also like the rail
Tyler: that this stuff travels on. So there's like, it's almost a good combinatorial explosion
Tyler: of like we have all these different protocols. A lot of them support multiple different
Tyler: rails.
Tyler: And it's like, yeah, my agent wants to pay using X402, using like USDC on base, but the
Tyler: merchant wants to receive via like MPP on like an OUSD on tempo. And then there's like,
Tyler: you know, Google's, I forget what it's called, they have one of these protocols too, and
Tyler: they just like want you to buy something with Visa.
Tyler: So there's just like this, you know, multidimensional explosion of possibilities. I don't
Tyler: know if I believe the thesis that like, blockchains and crypto assets are particularly
Tyler: good for micro payments or for, yeah, like machine payments, or yeah, like, it doesn't
Tyler: seem to me like some people frame it as if it's like, so obvious that it's inevitable
Tyler: that agents will use crypto assets. And I don't really agree with that yet. I think there
Tyler: are some pros for them to use that. But then I think there are some, you know, downsides.
Tyler: And so I think it's yet to be seen how it will play out.
Tyler: And like, for all the downsides of like the traditional rails, I think that those
Tyler: companies that control them and operate on them are like sprinting to make them more
Tyler: agent compatible.
Jackson: And what you're talking about is copium. I think that crypto people are hoping and coping
Jackson: that agents will use internet native money.
Chris: I completely agree. There's no reason. I think it's maybe a better outcome for the
Chris: commons if people settle on something that is like more open and more programmable. But
Chris: like, you know, at the end of the day, I think this whole standard score is emblematic of
Chris: like, how this works, which is that large players compete to capture the order flow.
Chris: And unless they're forced to use something incredibly neutral, they want, right?
Jackson: Absolutely. Yeah, I guess I could see letting an agent buy like things I don't care about,
Jackson: like the shoes. Getting cheap shoes, but I don't know, like groceries.
Tyler: I feel like groceries is like the perfect use case. You know, you tell the agent like, I
Tyler: like, you know, Mexican food and Thai food and like steak, like plan me, you know, three
Tyler: to four dinners for this week.
Tyler: Come up with a recipe, put the ingredients in my cart, buy them, have them delivered to
Tyler: my house and like send me an email, you know, at night with the recipe and which
Tyler: ingredients I'm supposed to use.
Tyler: Like that kind of thing, I think is something that people do for sure.
Jackson: I just don't trust it's going to like pick a good recipe and get me all the right
Jackson: ingredients to actually perform the cooking. But I don't know. I also very intense about
Tyler: my eating.
Tyler: Yeah, I know that you are such like a culinary aficionado. You are.
Jackson: Did you know my last name is Cook?
Chris: That's very important. Did you just dox yourself on the podcast? That's crazy. Jackson,
Jackson: swag dog, chef. You're just cook, you know?
Jackson: Swag dog is only visible in the stupid streaming software. Don't, don't expose me, man.
Tyler: I agree with that. I'm also very unsure and I'm not like the most informed on this. So I
Tyler: don't want to come out with like a very like, you know, a strong prediction.
Tyler: But it seems to me like a lot of the arguments I've heard about like why it will
Tyler: inevitably be some kind of crypto asset. They don't necessarily make sense to me.
Tyler: I think it is like a little bit of motivated reasoning. People want their coin, whether
Tyler: they're a company with a stable coin or a protocol or they're like a Bitcoin enthusiast.
Tyler: People want the thing that they're attached to, to like win and they'll motivated reason
Tyler: around it. It'll be interesting. I don't know. We'll see. I could see.
Jackson: In the end, it's the payment company that is like processing the payments on behalf of
Jackson: the vendor that's going to pick which protocols they support.
Tyler: It's kind of crazy that that whole thing relies basically on whatever the legislation was
Tyler: that like bans stable coins from passing interest on the consumers in the US.
Tyler: And it's like, oh, there will be this new business model because they can harvest all the
Tyler: interest. And it's like literally, oh, that business model only exists because the
Tyler: government banned them, like preventing a race to the bottom where they pass that
Tyler: interest back on to customers.
Chris: There's some kind of regulatory mode at play here, I think for sure.
Tyler: Yeah.
Jackson: Yeah, maybe we'll get to cover the genius act itself next week. I think that the deadline
Jackson: passed, but I'm glad we finally talked about it into payments.
Jackson: And that's, it looks like we're going to end this pot up two bucks. That's 2% on the hundo.
Chris: So I think we're building quite the nest egg for our retirement boys. I think you owe 5.6
Chris: an apology. Jackson, you're very scathing.
Jackson: I'm never, I'm never going to apologize.
Jackson: Yeah, I think we'll close it off there.
Jackson: And do you guys have any farewells to our, to our listeners?
Jackson: Oh, shoot. We're almost down.
Jackson: Quick. Close it. I'm going to close it right now.
Jackson: Close it.
Tyler: Sorry about all the puke talk earlier listeners.
Jackson: Yeah, we'll see what we do with that.
Chris: Claude, don't cut it out. Claude, make that the centerpiece of the podcast.
Jackson: All right.
Insert: Later.